Guide to the Frank Baker Collection of Wesleyana and British Methodism, 1536-1996 and undated RL.00413
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Wesley Family Series, 1700-1996 and undated, 18 boxes, approx. 1800 items
  - Wesley Family Portraits Subseries, 1703-1982 and undated, 13 boxes, approx. 1000 items
    - Wesley Family Portraits, Scenes, and Sites, 1740-1898 and undated, approximately 550 images
      - Samuel Wesley, Jr. (1690-1739) subject file, 1736, 1784-1812, and undated (Box WF8)
        Printed material and notes about Samuel Wesley, Jr., and his contemporaries, including approximately twenty plates and engravings of Alexander Pope, Jonathan Swift, and others; and title page from Poems on Several Occasions, 1736. Pope engraving bears signed inscription to Wesley, presumably a facsimile of Pope's hand.
      - Group scenes: The late Revd. John Wesley, M.A., and 446 of the Preachers in his Connexion represented as assembled in City Road Chapel, London, 1822 or 1823, B/W engraving, 32 x 23 (Box VM 31)
        Subject: JW addressing a throng of busts (mainly) of preachers from pulpit in left third of picture; in a lower pulpit or seat below him is Charles Wesley. Date is obscured by dirt and folds; newsprint was pasted to back at some point. Includes pictorial key of all 447 portraits.
      - Group scenes: 1898 and undated, 2 folders, 11 items (Box WF8 and WF11)
        Includes engravings of The First Wesleyan Conference and The Birthplace of the Rev. John Wesley, Epworth, among others.
      - Card series, undated (19th century), 3 folders, 55 items (Box WF8)
      - Other Wesley family members: Ancestors, parents, and siblings of JW and CW, circa 1731, 1780s, 1836, 1932 and undated, 15 items (Box WF8)
        Includes photograph of portrait of a Wesley family at Dangan Castle, attributed to William Hogarth, 1731.
      - Other Wesley family members: Wife, children, and descendents of CW, undated, 1824 and later, 11 items (Box WF8)
      - Wesleyan sites--various color and b/w engravings, 1740-1755, 1778, 1856-1859, and undated, 2 folders, 15 items (Box WF8 and WF11)
      - Wesley's Tree at Winchelsea, undated, 2 b/w engravings and 1 color postcard (Box WF8)
      - Scenes from the life of John Wesley, 1938 and undated, 6 items (Box WF8)
        20th Century B/W book illustration plates depicting scenes from John Wesley's life. Including "Beau Nash Interrupts John Wesley's Meeting," and "Wesley Preaching in Ireland" among others.
      - Portrait of Susanna Wesley, 1863 (Box WF11)
      - Group Portraits, 1801, 1820, and undated, 8 items (Box WF11)
        Includes portraits of Wesley alongside other prominent Methodist men, "Presidents of the Wesleyan Conference," and "Eminent Clergy of the 18th Century," among others.
      - Kingswood School, 1790 and undated, 5 items (Box WF11)
        One large engraving of the North-West view of Kingswood School, dedicated to John Wesley, engraved by Thomas McGeary. Also includes small, coloured engraving taken from McGeary's image and two other engravings depicting a different view of the school by J. McGahey as well as a letter to FB concerning the images.
      - Reminiscences of the Wesley Family, Epworth, published by J. Bottomley, photographer; dedicated to Rev. Charles Garrett, undated, after 1889, B/W print, 23.4 x 17.5 (Box WF12)
        Subject: series of eighteen Wesleyan places on one sheet, including: font at which JW was christened; cross and church from Queen Street; Old Rectory from which Wesley was rescued from fire at age six; Wesley Memorial Chapel spire from Burnham Road. B/W print with backgrounds tinted yellow.
      - Wesleyan Academy at Woodhouse Grove, near Leeds, Yorkshire, undated, B/W engraving, 20 x 16 (Box WF12)
      - Wesleyan portraits scrapbook, circa 1755-1882, approx. 122 pp. and 250 images (Box WF18)
        Scrapbook of engravings, printed materials, and short autograph documents featuring people, scenes, and sites of the early history of Methodism. JW (81 portraits and events) and other members of the Wesley family (Samuel, Susannah and Charles) are featured in first half of album, followed by other prominent 18th-19th century preachers and followers of Methodism. Clippings, programs, book covers and frontispieces, facsimiles, autographs, and a map. Also includes: two sets of autograph sermon notes in hand of John Fletcher (undated and unsigned); engraved facsimile of letter from JW, London, to Rev. Mr. Walker, Truro, 1755 Nov. 20 (penciled note corrects date to 1758); and other handwriting facsimiles from JW's inner circle. Other portraits include Joseph Benson, Thomas Coke, Adam Clarke, Alexander Mather, John Fletcher, George Whitefield, James Oglethorpe, the Countess of Huntingdon, and Francis Asbury. Asbury pages include early material on introduction of Methodism to United States. Title assigned by processor.
    - Roots of Methodism, circa late 1700s-1948 and undated (Box WF13-14)
      Collection of approximately 140 portrait and landscape engravings, clippings, photographs, and other materials relating to Wesley family and early background of Methodism. The original portfolio, received disbound, was compiled by Miss A.E.F. Barlow of Bolton, England, and given to scholar Frank Baker in 1948. It appears that other materials were mixed in at some point; these have the same general subject matter, though with a separate numbering scheme not reflected in the original index, which is housed in the first box. The second box predominantly consists of these additional materials. Portraits of the Wesleys appear in both groups of material.
      - Roots of Methodism --original list, 13 folders (Box WF13-14)
      - Roots of Methodism --additional materials, 6 folders (Box WF13-14)
- Correspondence Series, 1632-1637, 1710, 1738-1966, 1988, and undated, 17 boxes, approx. 3000 items
  Series is divided into thirty-six subseries for individuals and four subseries classified by groups. Primarily contains loose letters, letterbooks, broadsides, and other materials sent by and to Methodist ministers and laity from the time of the Wesleys through the 19th century. A significant portion of the material was created by people contemporary to the Wesleys. Some items are in short-hand - a sample of Wesley's own shorthand (without a key, however) is included in an information folder in box WF1.
  The series includes official and personal correspondence, theological discourse, poems, journals, biographies, and notes that reveal daily life among the early British Methodists, the external growth and internal establishment of Wesleyan Methodism, and important controversies in the church at the time, especially the Calvinist-Arminian controversy and arguments over the sacraments and the relationship of Methodism to the Anglican Church. There are also materials referring to ecclesiastical controversies after the death of the Wesleys.
  Other important topics include early Methodist missions; early training institutions; Methodism's relation to church and state; the split with the Church of England; and important debate over women preachers and the role overall of women in the church.
  - William Arthur Papers, 1842-1888 and undated, 20 items
    Letters and miscellaneous writings of William Arthur (1819-1901), Wesleyan Methodist minister, missionary to India (1839-1841), President of the Conference (1866), and prolific author. Among many other interests, Arthur vigorously supported the temperance movement and opposed slavery and Roman Catholicism. Correspondents include Jabez Bunting, George Osborn, and Morley Punshon.
    RELATED MATERIAL: Letters by and to Arthur also appear in the following series and subseries: Correspondence Series (Jabez Bunting and George Osborn); and Volumes Series, Letter Books Subseries: Simpson A, Simpson D, WP I, and WP II.
    - Twelve holograph letters, two FB transcriptions, one note with Bible verse, one autograph tract on shorthand, one verse from a Wesley poem ("Glory to God and Praise and Love") copied in Arthur's hand, and three printed items., 19 items (Box CO 1)
  - John Barnard Papers, 1632-1637, 22 items
    Letters and miscellaneous papers of John Barnard (fl. 1630s). Little is known about Barnard other than the brief information in the dealer's description, in Folder 1. He appears to have been a merchant in Hull; he also traveled to York and London, from where some of his letters to his wife are written. Letters are arranged in two folders of letters to his wife and a third folder of other documents.
    - Barnard, John, letters to his wife, 1636-1637, 2 folders (Box CO 1)
    - Letter to Barnard from a Tho[mas] Job?; and other documents, including a bill or shopping list, 1632 and undated (Box CO 1)
  - Joseph Benson Papers, 1771-1821 and undated, 36 items
    Letters and writings of Joseph Benson (1749-1821), Wesleyan Methodist itinerant minister who was twice President of the Conference (1798 and 1810) and editor of the Methodist Magazine from 1803-1821. Like his contemporary Thomas Coke, Benson was born early enough to know and correspond with many of the early figures of Methodism, including John and Charles Wesley, John and Mary Bosanquet Fletcher, and Selina Hastings, Countess of Huntingdon, but also lived well into the 19th century, witnessing the growth of the church in the generation following JW's death. Although the letters here cover some fifty years of his life, they cluster around two controversies in which he became embroiled in the early 1770s and the mid 1790s.
    Arranged in five folders: Folders 1-3, correspondence in chronological order; Folder 4, other documents; and Folder 5, oversize correspondence in a separate chronological sequence.
    RELATED MATERIAL: over eighty letters and printed items by, to, and about Joseph Benson appear at other points in this and other Frank Baker collections:
    Wesley Family Series, Charles Wesley (1707-1788)--letters to Benson
    Correspondence Series: John Fletcher, Mary Bosanquet Fletcher, and Selina Hastings, Countess of Huntingdon--letters to Benson
    Volumes Series, Letter Books Subseries and Scrapbooks Subseries--letters by and to Benson in several volumes
    Printed Materials Series, Broadsides and Circular Letters Subseries and Committee of Privileges Subseries
    Perronet Family Papers
    Frank Baker Papers, Subject Files: FB transcriptions of approximately fifty letters from other archives
    Wesley Family Papers
    - Buller, W., Bristol, to Mr. Jos. Benson, Brecknocks[hire?], 1771 Jan.9 (Box CO 1, Folder 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, n.p., to John Wesley, n.p., 1775 Oct. 23--Nov. (transcription) (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, n.p., to Mary Bosanquet, n.p., circa 1778 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, Leeds, to Miss North, Sheffield, 1782 May 20 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, Leeds, to Matthew Mayer, Cale-Green near Stockport, Cheshire, 1789 Aug. 7 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, n.p., to ?, n.p., 1794 Aug. 5 (Box CO 1)
    - Brown, Isaac, Leeds, to Joseph Benson, Bristol, 1794 Oct. 11 (Box CO 1)
    - Button, G, Ewhurst Green, to Joseph Benson, Bristol, 1794 Oct. 11 (Box CO 1)
    - Harrison, L[ancelot], Otley, to Mr. [Joseph] Benson, London, 1794 Oct. 18 (Box CO 1)
    - Jackson, Daniel, Bridlington, to Joseph Benson, Bristol, 1794 Oct. 18 (Box CO 1)
    - Botts, Samuel, Thilbale[? Hilvale?], to Joseph Benson, Bristol, 1794 Oct. 24 (Box CO 1)
    - Booth, John, Chester, to Mr. [Joseph] Benson, Bristol, 1794 Oct. 25 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, n.p., to H. W. Coulthurst, Halifax, 1796 Jan. 22 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, Hull, to Robert Stark, Rimswell near Patterington, 1797 Nov. 10 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, London, to Thomas Wood, Huddersfield, 1806 Mar. 8 (Box CO 1, Folder 2)
    - Benson, Joseph, London, to James MacDonald, n.p., 1809 July 13 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, London, to Mrs. McAllum, Canterbury, 1809 Sept. 15 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, London, to John Roadhouse, Sleaford, Lincolnshire, 1817 June 18 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, n.p., to James Everett, Lowgate, Hull, 1818 Feb. (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, London, to James Everett, Low-gate, Hull, 1819 Mar. 5 (Box CO 1)
    - Benson, Joseph, Bristol?, unaddressed fragment, undated (Box CO 1, Folder 3)
    - Death of Mr. Benson, 1821 (Box CO 1)
    - Bunting, Jabez, and George Marsden, London, "We have the painful intelligence to communicate, of the Death of our very highly respected and beloved Friend, Mr. Benson," 1821 Feb. 17 (Box CO 1)
    - Easton, John, William Holmes, and Robert C. Brackenbury, Poole, to [Joseph] Benson, New-Room Horse-Fair, Bristol, 1794 Oct. 10 (Box CO 1, Folder 4)
    - Watson, Richard, Wakefield, to [Joseph] [Benson], n.p., [1813 Oct. 13] (Box CO 1)
    - Joseph Benson's Birth Certificate, 1747/8 Feb. 21 [1948 transcription] (Box CO 1)
    - "Hymn for a Family" and "The True Use of Musick" by Charles Wesley, undated (Box CO 1)
      Transcription, six pages, as by C. Wesley; penciled note "This is Mr. Benson's writing."
    - Buller, Wm., Bristol, to Joseph Benson, n.p., 1771 Feb. 22 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.], Folder 5)
    - Hunsley, Mary, Beverley, to Joseph Benson, Birmingham, 1789 Oct. 28 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
    - Benson, Joseph, n.p., to Sarah (Sally) Wesley, Mar[l]y[e]bone, 1791 July 14 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
    - Anonymous, n.p., to Joseph Benson, Manchester, 1793 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
    - Coke, Thomas, Bristol, To the Preachers late in Connexion with the Rev. John Wesley, 1794 Aug. 18 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
    - Moore, Henry, Bristol, to Joseph Benson, n.p., 1794 Aug. 20 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
    - Coke, Thomas, and Samuel Bradburn, Bristol, to Joseph Benson, n.p., 1794 Aug. ?? (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
    - Benson, Joseph, near H[?]owden, to "Rev. & Dear Sir," n.p., 1797 Oct. 25 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
  - Samuel Bradburn Papers, 1792-1868, 8 items
    Letters, printed items, and other documents of Samuel Bradburn (1751-1816), Wesleyan Methodist minister and President of the Conference (1799). Printed letter from Bradburn in response to the Address of the Trustees of the Room and Guinea-Street Chapel, regarding controversy over whether to split from the Church of England, 1792 Oct. 5; 1896 copy of Bradburn's certificate of ordination, signed by Thomas Hanby, John Pawson, and Henry Taylor, 1792; 1868 article in the Methodist Magazine, quoting Bradburn's entire Preface to a small volume of hymns, 1806-07.
    RELATED MATERIAL: other printed letters about Bradburn's involvement in the controversies of the 1790s appear in the Printed Materials Series, Committee of Privileges Subseries; John Wesley's letters to Bradburn are in the John Steele volume in the Volumes Series, Letter Books Subseries.
    - Bradburn papers (Box CO 1)
  - Jabez Bunting Papers, 1810-1858 and undated, 37 items
    Letters, notes, printed materials, and other documents by or about Jabez Bunting (1779-1858), four-time President of the Wesleyan Methodist Conference (1820, 1828, 1836 and 1844). Bunting also served terms as either Secretary or Connexional Editor for most of the years from 1814-1827. A strong proponent of centralizing power in the Church, he also provoked much controversy and resistance, particularly the Wesleyan Reform movement and the anonymous "Fly Sheets" of the 1840s, which led to the expulsion of James Everett and two other ministers from the Conference. Arranged in three folders: (1) letters; (2) other documents; and (3) oversize materials.
    RELATED MATERIAL: Bunting appears at many other places in the collection as writer, recipient, or subject of letters and printed items. See especially the following series, subseries, and related collections:
    Correspondence Series, James Everett Papers
    Printed Materials Series, Broadsides and Circular Letters Subseries
    Volumes Series, Letter Books WP I and WP II
    Frank Baker Papers, Subject Files, Bunting (transcribed letters)
    Jabez Bunting Papers, 1838-1840,
    Rubenstein Library, Duke University
    - Williams, J., London, to Jabez Bunting, Sheffield, 1808 July 9 (Box CO 2, Folder 1)
    - Atmore, Charles, Leeds, to Jabez Bunting, Liverpool, 1810 Feb. 19 (Box CO 2)
    - Atmore, Charles, Hull, to Jabez Bunting, Halifax, 1812 Apr. 6 (Box CO 2)
    - Braithwaite, J., Chester, to Jabez Bunting, Halifax, 1812 June 8 (Box CO 2)
    - Holder, George, Whitby, to Jabez Bunting, Bristol, 1819 July 14 (and portrait of Holder) (Box CO 2)
    - King, John, Seven Oaks, to the Rev. Jabez Bunting, Bristol, 1819 July 26 (and portrait of King) (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, London, to ?, n.p., 1823 Mar. 18 (Box CO 2)
    - Wood, R., York, to J[abez] Bunting, Salford, Manchester, 1828 Dec. 6 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, Low Harrogate, to Isaac Keeling, Louth, Lincolnshire, 1833 Sep. 17 (Box CO 2)
    - Waddy, R[ichar]d, Wednesbury, to Jabez Bunting, London, 1835 Mar 31 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, London, to J. Broadhouse, Bedale, Yorkshire, 1835 Sep. 22 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, Hatton Garden, to Theophilus Lessey, Regents Park, 1839 Nov. 8 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, Wesleyan Mission House, London, to Ralph Scurrah, Boston, Lincolnshire, 1842 July 1 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, London, to ?, Bristol?, 1842 Sept. 10 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, London, to ?, n.p., 1842 Nov. 17 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, Brom'n(?), to W. Sharpe, Birmingham, 1844 Aug. 15 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, London, to W. Sharpe, Witney, 1844 Sept. 7 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, n.p., to John Beecham, London, 1844 Nov. 16 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, London, to Richardson (?), Hull, 1845 Jan. 6 (Box CO 2)
    - Stanley, Jacob, Bristol, to Rev. Dr. [Jabez] Bunting, London, 1845 Mar. 28 (Box CO 2)
    - Allen, James, Madeley, to Jabez Bunting, n.p., 1848 May 22 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, London, to John Powers, n.p., 1855 Aug. 30 (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, n.p., to Elijah Hoole, n.p., Thursday morning, 10 o'clock (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, n.p., to ?, n.p., undated (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, London, to ?, n.p., Friday afternoon (Box CO 2)
    - Bunting, Jabez, n.p., to William Arthur, n.p., undated (Box CO 2)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts and printed materials, 1801-1892 and undated, 10 items (Box CO 2, Folder 2)
      Various manuscript fragments and printed items, including: a letter of thanks to Bunting from the preachers admitted at Leeds, 1812; a poem about Bunting's preaching and asking for money, 1814; an anecdote in Bunting's hand, 1824, about JW's mission to Georgia; an obituary for Bunting and an order of service for his funeral at City Road Chapel, 1858 June 22.
    - Preaching-plan for Machester South Circuit, with notes of address on back, 1826 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.], Folder 3)
      RELATED MATERIAL: See also Bunting's handwritten Manchester plan for 1805-1806 in the Frank Baker Collection of Methodist Circuit Plans.
    - Memo on 'The Nature and Extent of the Subordination [or Missionaries to the Mission Committee]', [date??] (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
  - Joseph Butterworth Papers, 1803-1820, 5 items
    Letters and documents of Joseph Butterworth (1770-1826), publisher, politician, and the second Methodist Member of Parliament (for Coventry, 1812-1818, and Dover, 1820-1826). Butterworth was one of the founding members of the Committee of Privileges, and oversize documents below may pertain to that.
    RELATED MATERIAL: Many documents in the Printed Materials Series, Committee of Privileges Subseries are authored or co-authored by Butterworth.
    - Butterworth, Joseph, Layman, Battel, Sussex, to [Bunting??], n.p., 1817 Sept. 10 (Box CO 2, Folder 1 of 2)
    - Butterworth, Joseph, London, to Mrs. Adam Clarke, n.p., 1818 (Box CO 2)
    - Butterworth, Joseph, Bedford Square, to Miss Mary Ann Clarke, n.p., 1820 June 20 (Box CO 2)
    - Butterworth, Joseph, the Secretary to the Methodist Committee, to The Right Hon'ble The Secretary at War, 1803 July 20 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.], Folder 2 of 2)
      Together on same sheet w/letter signed William Myles, Chairman, Wednesday Morning 20th July 1803, New Chapel City Road. This and following item may be contemporary copies of original documents related to the Committee of Privileges--see Printed Materials Series, Committee of Privileges Subseries.
    - Butterworth, Joseph, to Joseph Benson, 1803 July 26 (Box CO 17 [ovsz.])
      Copy of pages 1-5 of letter; then note "6 7 8 have not time to copy--see page 9 to follow here". P. 9 then follows, in the same new hand that picked up in middle of p. 5; then a 10th unnumbered page and Butterworth's signature (the 2nd hand that began on p.5 appears to be his)
  - Adam Clarke Papers, 1788-1859, 46 items
    Letters, manuscripts, and other documents of Adam Clarke (1762-1832), Wesleyan Methodist minister and three-time President of the Conference (1806, 1814, 1822), and of his immediate family. Clarke was a central figure in early Methodism and no stranger to controversy, combating poverty and slavery, supporting more lay involvement (even of women), and holding an adoptionist view of Jesus' sonship. A respected scholar and linguist, Clarke supported foreign missions and the Bible Society.
    Arranged in seven folders: (1-3) letters of Adam Clarke, chronological; (4) letters of Clarke family, chronological; (5-6) miscellaneous writing and family documents; (7) oversize materials.
    RELATED MATERIAL:
    Adam Clarke Papers, ca. 1762-1832,
    - Clarke, Adam, and Susanne and Joan de Queteville, n.p., to Madame De Jersey, Montplaisir, Guernsey, 1788 Oct. 31 (Box CO 2, Folder 1 of 7)
    - Pencil Rubbing of Seal of Adam Clarke, seal 1788 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Bristol, to Mr. Bowen, Watchmaker, Clerkenwell, London, 1799 Mar 30-1801 Aug. 28 (4 letters) (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Manchester, to Joseph Butterworth, and Christopher Sundius, n.p., 1805 Mar 26 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Manch (ester), to Mr. Buttress, London, 1805 Apr. 16 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Dublin, to Mrs. Mary Clarke, London, 1811 June 5 (Box CO 2, Folder 2 of 7)
    - Clarke, Adam, London, to The Rev. Mr. Blackett, Coventry, 1813 Mar 27 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, and Thomas Coke, n.p., to Rev. Beaumont, n.p., 1814 or earlier (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, n.p., to Miss MacMullin, Bath, 1815 June 28 (Box CO 2)
    - Colchester, Lord, n.p., to Adam Clarke, Hilbrooke, 1817 Oct 30 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Millbrook, to Theo James Clarke, London, 1820 Oct. 22 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, n.p., to Jacob Stanley, Dudley, 1820 Nov 29 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, n.p., to Mr. Byram, Surveyor, Liverpool, 1821 May 24 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Millbrook, to Daniel Isaacs, n.p., 1822 Apr. 17 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, n.p., to Rev. J. Gualter, n.p., 1822 Apr. 17 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Millbrook, to Robert Newton, Manchester, 1822 Nov. 18 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Prescot, to The Rev. Daniel Isaacs, Leicester, 1823 May 21 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, n.p., to Butterworth, n.p., 1826 Apr 16 (Box CO 2, Folder 3 of 7)
    - Clarke, Adam, n.p., to Mary [Ann] Smith, Stoke Newington, 1826 Dec. 12 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Eastcott, near Pinner, to A. Mackintosh, Gossaburg(h), Isle of Yell, 1827 Nov. 28 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, near Pinner, to The Rev. Mr. Archdeacon (Francis) Wrangham, n.p., 1828 Jan. 20 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Pinner, Middlesex, to ?, n.p., 1828 Nov. 29 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Pinner, Middlesex, to A. Mackintosh, North Marin, Shetland, 1829 Feb 9 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Eastcott near Pinner, Middlesex, to Mr. Bowen, Watchmaker, Piccadilly, 1829 June 22 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, Adam, Liverpool, to ?, n.p., 1832 July 25 (Box CO 2)
    - Clarke, J[oseph] B.B., n.p., to H[ugh] S[tuart] Boyd, Esq., York Terrace, Sidmouth, Devonshire, 1831 or later (watermark) (Box CO 2, Folder 4 of 7)